export const chapter = "Chapter - 18: Atmosphere : Wind and Moisture";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What causes atmospheric pressure?",
        optionA: "Earth's rotation",
        optionB: "Gravitational force",
        optionC: "Wind patterns",
        correctAnswer: "B) Gravitational force",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why do mountaineers need oxygen cylinders when scaling high peaks?",
        optionA: "High humidity",
        optionB: "Low atmospheric pressure",
        optionC: "High atmospheric pressure",
        correctAnswer: "B) Low atmospheric pressure",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the main instrument used to measure atmospheric pressure?",
        optionA: "Thermometer",
        optionB: "Barometer",
        optionC: "Anemometer",
        correctAnswer: "B) Barometer",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the unit for measuring atmospheric pressure?",
        optionA: "Pascal",
        optionB: "Bar",
        optionC: "Millibar",
        correctAnswer: "C) Millibar",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What causes the creation of high and low pressure belts on Earth?",
        optionA: "Rotation of the Moon",
        optionB: "Rotation of the Earth",
        optionC: "Movement of ocean currents",
        correctAnswer: "B) Rotation of the Earth",
      },
      {
        question: "What are the winds blowing from the east direction called?",
        optionA: "Westerlies",
        optionB: "Trade winds",
        optionC: "Monsoons",
        correctAnswer: "B) Trade winds",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of rainfall occurs when moist wind rises over a mountain?",
        optionA: "Convectional rainfall",
        optionB: "Relief rainfall",
        optionC: "Cyclonic rainfall",
        correctAnswer: "B) Relief rainfall",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the center of a cyclone called?",
        optionA: "Storm eye",
        optionB: "Cyclone core",
        optionC: "Wind center",
        correctAnswer: "A) Storm eye",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the term for the actual amount of water vapor present in the air?",
        optionA: "Absolute humidity",
        optionB: "Relative humidity",
        optionC: "Dew point",
        correctAnswer: "A) Absolute humidity",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What process involves water changing into ice or snow in the atmosphere?",
        optionA: "Condensation",
        optionB: "Evaporation",
        optionC: "Precipitation",
        correctAnswer: "A) Condensation",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Natural vegetation is an important ___________ resource. Life is said to have first appeared on the earth in the form of vegetation. All living beings depend on it for food directly or indirectly.",
        optionA: "Renewable",
        optionB: "Valuable",
        optionC: "Essential",
        correctAnswer: "B) Valuable",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The type of natural vegetation at a place depends upon several factors, such as ___________.",
        optionA: "Wind patterns",
        optionB: "Temperature and moisture",
        optionC: "Altitude",
        correctAnswer: "B) Temperature and moisture",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Big trees thrive in the areas of heavy rainfall. The size of trees reduces with the reduction in the amount of rainfall. Short stunted trees and grasses grow in the regions of moderate rainfall, where ___________ are formed.",
        optionA: "Deserts",
        optionB: "Rainforests",
        optionC: "Grasslands",
        correctAnswer: "C) Grasslands",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Thorny scrubs and shrubs grow in dry areas where rainfall is highly deficient. In such areas, plants have deep roots and their leaves have thorny and waxy surfaces which help to reduce ___________.",
        optionA: "Erosion",
        optionB: "Transpiration",
        optionC: "Evaporation",
        correctAnswer: "B) Transpiration",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The major vegetation types may be classified as forests, grasses, scrubs, and ___________.",
        optionA: "Wetlands",
        optionB: "Tundra",
        optionC: "Swamps",
        correctAnswer: "B) Tundra",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Plants give us food, timber, medicines, and several other forest products. They give shelter and shade to wildlife, protect the soil from erosion, check the water current, and also help in ___________ of water.",
        optionA: "Desalination",
        optionB: "Filtration",
        optionC: "Seepage",
        correctAnswer: "C) Seepage",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Forests can be broadly divided into two types: evergreen and ___________.",
        optionA: "Desert",
        optionB: "Semi-arid",
        optionC: "Deciduous",
        correctAnswer: "C) Deciduous",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India has varied physical features, climates, soils, altitudes, etc., so different types of forests are found in India. The following five major types of natural vegetation are found in India, including tropical evergreen forests and tropical ___________ forests.",
        optionA: "Polar",
        optionB: "Deciduous",
        optionC: "Desert",
        correctAnswer: "B) Deciduous",
      },
      {
        question:
          "There is a need to make a serious effort to conserve wildlife from becoming completely extinct. In addition to the conservation of forests and habitats of different animals, the government should regulate whenever forest land is needed for any projects like roads or ___________.",
        optionA: "Factories",
        optionB: "Settlement",
        optionC: "Parks",
        correctAnswer: "B) Settlement",
      },
      {
        question:
          "National parks and sanctuaries should be established to conserve rare species, and awareness programs should be launched for this purpose. The balance in the environment can be maintained only when the relative number of wildlife species, forests, and other factors are not ___________.",
        optionA: "Disturbed",
        optionB: "Protected",
        optionC: "Enhanced",
        correctAnswer: "A) Disturbed",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Natural vegetation is only valuable for human beings.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Temperature and moisture are not factors that influence the type of natural vegetation at a place.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Grasslands are formed in regions of heavy rainfall.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Thorny scrubs and shrubs grow in areas with high rainfall.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tundra is a major vegetation type that includes forests, grasses, and scrubs.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Plants play no role in the filtration of water.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "All forests can be broadly classified into two types: evergreen and desert.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The type of natural vegetation in India includes only polar forests.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Government regulations are not needed when forest land is required for projects like roads or settlements.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The balance in the environment can be maintained without concern for the relative number of wildlife species, forests, and other factors.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
